Guide to the Human Relations Area Files Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Human Relations Area Files records
1947-1962
RU 476
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
0.5
(2 boxes)
The records consist of minutes, correspondence, memoranda, bibliographies, reports, and papers documenting the activities and operations of the Human Relations Area Files.
Human Relations Area Files, inc
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 37 (YRG 37), Records of associations, institutes, centers, and organizations affiliated with Yale University.
Arrangement
The records are arranged by accession.
Biographical / Historical
The Human Relations Area Files (HRAF) was founded at Yale University in 1949. Its mission is to "encourage and facilitate worldwide comparative studies of human behavior, society, and culture."
Scope and Contents
The records consist of minutes, correspondence, memoranda, bibliographies, reports, and papers documenting the activities and operations of the Human Relations Area Files.
Anthropology -- Research; Ethnology -- Research; Research institutes; Human Relations Area Files, inc
- Records, 1947-1962; Accession 1989-A-103
  - Allan Holmsberg correspondence and involvement in Human Relations Area Files, 1949-1955 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Agendae and minutes of meetings, 1949-1955 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Information for the 1954 Annual Meeting (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Other letters, 1947-1952 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Bylaws, 1954-1955 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Financial statements, 1951-1957 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Minutes of meetings, 1950-1962 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Technical, 1950-1952 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - "Systematic Source Files on Cultures and Areas: The Cross-Cultural Survey and Related Projects", 1948 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - "A Report on the Present Status of the Human Relations Area Files", [1954] (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - "Annual Report of the Human Relations Area Files, Incorporated to the State University of Iowa Administration", 1955 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Memoranda, 1950-1956 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Notices of shipments, 1953-1962 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Status report, undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - First Year Program bibliographies, undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Second Year Program bibliographies, undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Third Year Program bibliographies, undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Bibliography on Formosans, undated (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Bibliography on Czechoslovakia, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Bibliography on Aleut, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Research plans, 1956-1957 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Annual Meeting: 9-11 May, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Papers and Materials for Annual Meeting: 9-11 May, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Annual Meeting: 3-4 May, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Guest Book, 1948-1957 (Box 1)
- Guest book, 1948-1957; Accession 1991-A-047
  General note
  See: 1989-A-103, box 1